A Finding Aid to the Esther McCoy Papers, circa 1876-1990, bulk 1938-1989, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccoesth
Archives of American Art
- Architectural Writings, 1908-1990; Series 4; (Boxes 14-24, 42, 49, 50; 10.2 linear feet)
  - Books, 1908-1988; 4.1
    - Contemporary Architects, Various Essays, 1978-1985 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Craig Ellwood: Architecture (1969) (Box 14)
      - Drafts, circa 1968 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Project Documents, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Five California Architects (1960, 1975) (Box 14)
      - Acknowledgements and Introduction, circa 1975 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Captions and Credits, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence (photocopies), 1908, 1911-1918, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence, circa 1956-1963 (Box 14, Folder 36-38)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1987 (Box 14, Folder 39-40)
      - Drafts and Notes, Irving Gill, 1950s (Box 14, Folder 41-46)
      - Drafts and Notes, Bernard Maybeck, 1950s (Box 14, Folder 47-49)
      - Drafts and Notes, Bernard Maybeck, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
      - Drafts and Notes, R. M. Schindler, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 3-7)
      - Financial Records, 1959-1965, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Notes, Greene and Greene, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Photographs, Irving Gill, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Photographs, Bernard Maybeck, circa 1959 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Publicity and Reviews, circa 1959-1975 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Research Material, Irving Gill, 1922-1933, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Research Material, Bernard Maybeck, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Symposium and Home Tour, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Francisco Artigas (1972; Foreword and Introduction by Esther McCoy) (Box 15)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Foreword, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Illustrations, circa 1971 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Interview Transcripts, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Introduction, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Notes, circa 1971 (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
    - Macmillan Encyclopedia of Architects, Various Essays, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 23-24)
    - Modern California Houses: Case Study Houses 1946-1962 (1962, 1977) (Box 15)
      - Bibliography, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Blueprints, Craig Ellwood, Case Study House #16 (Salzman House), 1952; (Oversized rolled items housed in RD 49) (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Blueprints, Charles Eames, Case Study Houses #8 and #9, circa 1949; (Oversized rolled items housed in RD 50) (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1965, 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - Draft Fragments, circa 1962 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Drafts, First Edition, circa 1962 (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - Drafts, Second Edition, circa 1977 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Notes and Research Material, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 32-33)
      - Photographs, circa 1940s-1950s; (Julius Shulman and Marvin Rand photographs not scanned.) (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1962-1978 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Richard Neutra (1960) (Box 15)
      - Correspondence, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - Drafts and Notes, 1950s-1960 (Box 15, Folder 37-39)
      - Printed Material, circa 1960, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - The Second Generation (1984) (Box 15)
      - Bibliography, Captions, and Index, circa 1980s (Box 15, Folder 41-42)
      - Building Plans used in Book, circa 1970s (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - Corrections to Galleys, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence, General, 1977-1987 (Box 15, Folder 45-48)
      - Correspondence, Gregory Ain, 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, J. R. Davidson, circa 1965-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Harwell Harris, 1978-1984 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
      - Drafts, Gregory Ain, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 6-12)
      - Drafts, J. R. Davidson, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 13-16)
      - Drafts, Harwell Harris, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 17-22)
      - Drafts, Raphael Soriano, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
      - Financial Records, 1976, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Notes and Research Material, Gregory Ain, 1955, 1960s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 26-28)
      - Notes and Research Material, J. R. Davidson, circa 1960s-1980s; (oversized items housed in Box 42) (Box 16, Folder 29-32)
      - Notes and Research Material, General, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
      - Notes and Research Material, Harwell Harris, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 3-7)
      - Notes and Research Material, Raphael Soriano, 1956-1982 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
      - Publicity and Reviews, circa 1984-1986 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Vienna to Los Angeles: Two Journeys (1979) (Box 17)
      - Acknowledgements and Bibliography, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Article, "Letters Between R. M. Schindler and Richard Neutra, 1914-1924" by Esther McCoy, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 12-15)
      - Correspondence, General, circa 1958-1980 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, Philip and David Lovell (photocopies), 1926-1928, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, Erich Mendelsohn (photocopies), 1922 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, Pauline Schindler (photocopies), 1930-1976 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, R. M. Schindler (photocopies), circa 1914-1954 (Box 17, Folder 20-22)
      - Correspondence, R. M. Schindler correspondence with Richard Neutra (photocopies), 1912-1924 (Box 17, Folder 23-25)
      - Correspondence, R. M. Schindler correspondence with Richard Neutra, Draft Translations, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
      - Correspondence, R. M. Schindler correspondence with Richard Neutra, Typescripts, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 28-32)
      - Correspondence, Frank Lloyd Wright re: Barnsdall House (photocopies), circa 1916-1925, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 33-36)
      - Draft One, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Draft Two, circa 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Draft Fragments, circa 1970s (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Essay, "Taliesin in 1919" by Pauline Schindler, circa 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Foreword, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Introduction, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Notes and Research Material, 1928-1970s (Box 18, Folder 6-14)
      - Photographs and Captions, circa 1910-1979; (Julius Shulman photographs not scanned.) (Box 18, Folder 15-21)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Oversized Blueprints, Case Study House #16, 1952; (Scanned with Box 15, Folder 26) (Box RD 49)
    - Oversized Blueprints, Case Study Houses #8 and #9, circa 1949; (Scanned with Box 15, Folder 27) (Box RD 50)
    - Oversized Notes and Research Material, J. R. Davidson, circa 1960s-1980s; (Scanned with Box 16, Folders 29-32) (Box 42)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1942-1990; 4.2
    This subseries contains records of McCoy's work on several exhibition catalogs. McCoy worked on major museum exhibitions about architecture, such as Blueprints for Modern Living at the Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles; Ten Italian Architects at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art; and High Styles at the Whitney Museum of American Art. In some instances she was a curator for the exhibition and wrote the catalog, and in others she was asked to contribute an essay for the catalog. Files include correspondence, published catalogs, draft writings and photographs used for the catalogs, notes and research material, publicity and reviews, and other documentation of exhibition details. Of particular note are a video about the Case Study House Program that was released in conjunction with the Blueprints for Modern Living exhibition, and documentation regarding theft of items from the Juan O'Gorman exhibition.
    Files are grouped alphabetically by exhibition title.
    - A. Quincy Jones: A Tribute (1980) (Box 18)
      - Catalog, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Drafts, circa 1979 (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
      - Notes and Research Material, circa 1970s-1980 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Blueprints for Modern Living: History and Legacy of the Case Study House (1989) (Box 18)
      - Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Drafts, circa 1989 (Box 18, Folder 28-29)
      - Notes, circa 1989 (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Project Description, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Video, "The Case Study House Program, 1945-1966,", 1989; (1 videocassette (VHS)) (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Felix Candela (1957) (Box 18)
      - Catalog and Printed Material, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 18, Folder 35-36)
      - Drafts and Notes, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 37-38)
      - Exhibition Arrangements, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 39)
      - Photographs, circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - High Styles (1986) (Box 18)
      - Checklist Documents, circa 1985 (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 18, Folder 42-44)
      - Drafts, circa 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
      - Exhibition Arrangements, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Fabric Samples, circa 1956-1968 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Museum Catalog Records (photocopies), circa 1985 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Notes, circa 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, circa 1942-1985; (photographs by Julius Shulman and Marvin Rand not scanned) (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
      - Research Material, circa 1960s-1985 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Reviews, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
    - Home Sweet Home: The California Ranch House (1983) (Box 19)
      - Correspondence and Exhibition Planning Documents, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Drafts, circa 1983 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Notes, circa 1983 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Photographs, 1945, 1958, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Printed Material, 1971, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Irving Gill (1958) (Box 19)
      - Catalog, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Drafts, circa 1958 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Exhibition Arrangements, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Photographs for Catalog, 1958; (photographs by Marvin Rand not scanned) (Box 19, Folder 21-23)
    - Juan O'Gorman (1964) (Box 19)
      - Catalog, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence, 1958, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Drafts and Exhibition Arrangements, circa 1958-1964 (Box 19, Folder 26-27)
      - Report on Theft, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Marmo: The New Italian Stone Age, Introduction by Esther McCoy, circa 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Naives and Visionaries (1975) (Box 19)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1977, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - Drafts, circa 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - Notes, circa 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 32)
      - Photographs, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - Printed Material, 1967-1981 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Ten Italian Architects (1967) (Box 19)
      - Acknowledgements and Captions, circa 1967 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      - Blueprints, Ignazio Gardella, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      - Catalog, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 19, Folder 38-40)
      - Financial Records, circa 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 41)
      - Notebooks, circa 1963-1967 (Box 19, Folder 42-44)
      - Notes, circa 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
      - Photograph Album, circa 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Proposals, circa 1964 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Publicity, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Research Material, Franco Albini, circa 1963-1965 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Research Material, General, circa 1957-1966 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Research Material, Angelo Mangiarotti, 1963-1968 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Research Material, Gino Valle, circa 1960s (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Journals, Magazines, and Newspapers, 1948-1989; 4.3
    This subseries documents McCoy's work for journals, magazines, and newspapers, including publications for which she was a contributing editor, such as Arts and Architecture, Lotus, and Progressive Architecture. Articles are primarily on the topic of architecture, but also include a few writings on design, art, crafts, and travel. Files generally contain drafts of articles and related notes, but may also include related correspondence and photographs, as well as a clipping of the published article. Also found are general correspondence files regarding her work as an editor for Arts and Architecture, Progressive Architecture, and Lotus.
    McCoy also worked for nearly two decades as a free lance writer for the L. A. Times, primarily writing about architecture and travel for the Home Magazine supplement. Found here are numerous draft articles, including regular features on California architects, and writings about Italy and Mexico.
    Of note are articles on young architects written for Arts and Architecture and Zodiac magazines, an article on Brasilia for the L. A. Times, and an article about the Charles Eames office for Progressive Architecture.
    Titles of publications found in this subseries are arranged alphabetically, and individual articles are arranged chronologically by publication date. The exact publication date, when known, is given in parentheses.
    - AIA Review, "The Dodge House,", 1965 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - AIA Review, "Is Mies Doing Anything Interesting?,", 1968 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Angeles, "Homage to Reyner Banham" (September 1988) (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Architectural Digest, "City Map Guide No. 23: Los Angeles" (No. 7), 1974 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Architectural Forum, "Dr. Salk Talks about His Institute" (December 1967) (Box 20, Folder 14-15)
    - Architectural Forum, "A Health Center with Muscles" (March 1969) (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Architecture, Review: "R. M. Schindler by August Sarnitz,", 1989 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Architecture and Urbanism, "Venturi, Rauch, and Scott Brown" (December 1981) (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Arts & Architecture (Box 20)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1966, 1982, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 19-20)
      - "Architecture in Mexico" (August 1951) (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - "The New University City of Mexico" (August 1952) (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - "The Bradbury Building" (April 1953), circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 23-24)
      - "Notes on Greene and Greene" (July 1953) (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - "Four Houses of the '20s by R. M. Schindler, Architect" (September 1953) (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - "R. M. Schindler 1890-1953" (May 1954) (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - "Weaving by Saul Borisov" (June 1954) (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - "Pier Luigi Nervi - Concrete Sections from Two New Stadiums" (September 1956) (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - "Concrete Shell Forms - Felix Candela" (May 1957) (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - "Tribute to Sardinia" (November 1962) (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - "William Morris, Designer, Craftsman, Victorian" (March 1963), 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 32-33)
      - "Italian Designs" (May 1963) (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - "Mosaics of Juan O'Gorman" (February 1964) (Box 20, Folder 35)
      - "West Coast Architects II: William Wilson Wurster" (July 1964) (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - "West Coast Architects III: Victor Gruen" (October 1964) (Box 20, Folder 37)
      - "Pure Research,", 1964 (Box 20, Folder 38)
      - "West Coast Architects V: John Lautner" (August 1965) (Box 20, Folder 39)
      - "Young Architects: The Small Office" (February-March, 1966), circa 1962-1966 (Box 20, Folder 40-43)
      - [Death of Susan Jonas,], circa 1960s (Box 20, Folder 44)
      - "Gregory Ain" (Winter 1981), 1979-1982 (Box 20, Folder 45)
      - "The Greenhouse" (Spring 1982), circa 1982 (Box 20, Folder 46)
      - "The Death of Juan O'Gorman" (Spring 1982) (Box 20, Folder 47)
      - "Garrett Eckbo: The Early Years" (Fall 1982) (Box 20, Folder 48)
      - "Retrospect: Bruce Goff" (Summer 1983) (Box 20, Folder 49)
      - "John Entenza" (Winter 1984) (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Arts in Society, "Avant-Garde Architecture" (1962) (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - California Magazine, "Geography as Destiny" (March 1986) (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - California Magazine, "Ray Eames" (1988) (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Design Book Review, "On the Edge of the World by Richard Longstreth" (1983, December 23) (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Design Quarterly, "Charles and Ray Eames" (1975), circa 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Domus, "Review: Bruce Goff in Architecture" (July 1971), 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Domus, "Post-Mies: Architecture di Anthony J. Lumsden" (November 1975), circa 1975 (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - Global Architecture, "Gunnar Birkerts" (Volume 31), circa 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 58-60)
    - Harvard Architecture Review, "Post Modern: Pelli and Gehry" (Unpublished), 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 61-62)
    - Historic Preservation, "Irving Gill, Architect" (April-June 1972) (Box 20, Folder 63)
    - Hudson Review, "Luis Barragan,", 1989 (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - Journal of Architectural Education, Review of Beyond Metabolism: The New Japanese Architecture by Michael Franklin Ross, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 65)
    - Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians, "Letters from Louis H. Sullivan to R. M. Schindler" (December 1961) (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - L. A. Architect (Box 21)
      - "J. R. Davidson" (May 1977) (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "A Walk with Lutah Riggs" (July 1979) (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "Obituary: A. Quincy Jones: 1913-1979" (September 1979) (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "Gio Ponti: 1891-1979" (November 1979) (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "Konrad Wachsman: 1901-1980" (January 1981) (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "Ray Eames" (October 1988) (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles Herald Examiner (Box 21)
      - Article on Craig Ellwood, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "Case Study House #17" (1956, April 8) (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "Candela Exhibition" (1957, April 28) (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - "Los Angeles: A Private Proving Ground" (1980, February 6) (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles Times (Box 21)
      - Home Magazine, "Mexico" Issue (1952, October 19) (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "Then and Now" (1952, December 14) (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - "House With Sloping Walls,", 1952 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - "Who Starts a Style?" (1953, July 19) (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - "Northwest Roundup,", 1953 (Box 21, Folder 17-20)
      - Home Magazine, "Mexico" Issue (1954, January 24) (Box 21, Folder 21-22)
      - "La Jolla's First Architect" (1954, March 28) (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - "60 Years of Architectural Progress Hailed by AIA" (1954, August 29) (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (J. R. Davidson, 1954, November 21) (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (Gregory Ain, 1955, January 2), 1954 (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (Thornton Abell, 1955, May 1) (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (John Lautner, 1955, May 16) (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - "Great Maya Builders of Yucatan" (September 1955) (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (Irving Gill, 1955, November 6) (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (George Russell, 1955, November 20) (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - "Bolton Hall,", 1955-1980s (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - "The Subject of the Researches is Man" (1956, January 22) (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (A. Quincy Jones and Frederick Emmons, 1956, February 19) (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - "California Landscaping No. 1" (1956, February 26) (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (Richard Neutra, 1956, March 18) (Box 21, Folder 36)
      - "California Landscaping No. 2" (1956, May 13) (Box 21, Folder 37)
      - "Salute to AIA, Well Earned" (1956, May 13) (Box 21, Folder 38)
      - "What I Believe? A Statement of Architectural Principles" (Milton Sessions, 1956, November 18) (Box 21, Folder 39)
      - "Roots of California Contemporary Architecture,", circa 1956 (Box 21, Folder 40)
      - "California Landscaping No. 9" (1957, April 21) (Box 21, Folder 41)
      - "Italy Boasts Finest Greek Marble" (1958, February 2) (Box 21, Folder 42)
      - "Where to Look for Arts and Crafts on Travels Abroad" (1958, April 2) (Box 21, Folder 43)
      - "In Sardinia Design is Ruled by Spontaneity" (1958, October 14), 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 44-46)
      - "The War and Ensenada" (1958, November 16) (Box 21, Folder 47)
      - Various Articles on Italian Crafts, circa 1958 (Box 21, Folder 48)
      - "Those Crazy Domes" (1959, February 22), circa 1959 (Box 21, Folder 49)
      - "Room for 2 Million in the Hills" (1959, March 18), circa 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 50)
      - "Italy's Marble" (1959, November 1) (Box 21, Folder 51-52)
      - "Brasilia" (1959, November 22), Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 53)
      - "Brasilia" (1959, November 22), Notes and Research Material, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 54)
      - "Brasilia" (1959, November 22), Photographs, circa 1959 (Box 21, Folder 55-56)
      - "The Time Kendall Tried to Build a Modern House" (1960, March 20) (Box 21, Folder 57)
      - "Chess in Cuernavaca" (1960, July 31) (Box 21, Folder 58)
      - "Wanted: Architect (preferably a dead one)" (1960, August 21) (Box 21, Folder 59)
      - "Israeli Craft: A Fusion of Many Cultures" (1960, October 9 and 1961, June 4), 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 60-62)
      - "Flying off the Handle at International Airport" (1962, October 14) (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - "Santa Monica's Inspiration Point - It's at End of the Line" (1962, October 28) (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - "Megastructures for Megalopoli" (1967, January 15), 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 65)
      - "Richard Neutra" (1968, February 11), 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 66)
      - "Architecture in California: 1868-1968," (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - Various Articles, circa 1957-1977 (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Lotus (Box 21)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1983 (Box 21, Folder 69-71)
        (Includes general correspondence with editor, Bruno Alfieri)
      - "Buildings in the United States, 1966-1967" (1967-1968, v. 4), 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 72-74)
      - "R. M. Schindler" (1968, v. 5) (Box 21, Folder 75)
      - Documents used for Lotus 5, circa 1968 (Box 21, Folder 76)
      - "17 Miles Between Mesa and Apache Junction" (1974, v. 8) (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - Mademoiselle's Living (Box 21)
      - "Two Grangers in Three Acts,", 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 78)
      - "Kirk House on Finn Hill, Seattle,", 1949 (Box 21, Folder 79)
      - "Gregory Ain's Mar Vista Project for Veterans,", 1950 (Box 21, Folder 80)
      - "Kumler House, Phoenix, Arizona,", 1950-1951 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - New West, "Palms" (1976, June 7) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - New York Times, Article on Japanese Design, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Pacific Spectator, "West Coast Architecture: A Romantic Movement Ends,", 1952 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Perspecta, "Case Study Houses" (1976, v. 15), circa 1976 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
    - Progressive Architecture (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1964, 1969-1974 (Box 22, Folder 6-10)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1989 (Box 22, Folder 11-15)
      - Financial Records, 1969-1976 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - General Notes, 1966-circa 1970s (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "Owens Valley Study,", circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - "Central City" (March 1970) (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - "Who's Hurting Here" (July 1971) (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - "Designing for a Dry Climate" (1971, n. 8) (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - "Toward the G Intensity Silhouette,", circa 1971 (Box 22, Folder 22-23)
      - "Performing Arts Building, UC Santa Cruz,", 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 24)